<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://juiceshaman.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://juiceshaman.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-04-29T12:19:17+00:00</updated><id>https://juiceshaman.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>This blog is a collection on my current take on existence as well as other interesting artefacts I might have picked uo along the ride.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Goodmorning</title><link href="https://juiceshaman.github.io/blog/2023/getting-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodmorning" /><published>2023-04-23T18:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-23T18:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://juiceshaman.github.io/blog/2023/getting-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://juiceshaman.github.io/blog/2023/getting-up/"><![CDATA[<p>Ever noticed, how different thoughts arise during the day? Varying depending on context of inner and outer reality. One striking example of this is how when one wakes up and stays in bed, there seem to not come any “good” thoughts to mind. Conversely, getting up out of bed and starting your day jump starts the fabrication of ideas (e.g. commitments made, wishes for the future, possibilites and events). I am close to believing that no good thoughts can arise from staying in bed when awake and for me this might be the single most effective factor for a more thoughtful and aware relationship to this existence.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="shorts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever noticed, how different thoughts arise during the day? Varying depending on context of inner and outer reality. One striking example of this is how when one wakes up and stays in bed, there seem to not come any “good” thoughts to mind. Conversely, getting up out of bed and starting your day jump starts the fabrication of ideas (e.g. commitments made, wishes for the future, possibilites and events). I am close to believing that no good thoughts can arise from staying in bed when awake and for me this might be the single most effective factor for a more thoughtful and aware relationship to this existence.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moving Closer!</title><link href="https://juiceshaman.github.io/blog/2022/flowstates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving Closer!" /><published>2022-04-23T16:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T16:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://juiceshaman.github.io/blog/2022/flowstates</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://juiceshaman.github.io/blog/2022/flowstates/"><![CDATA[<p>Every once in a while we get these glimpses into what scientists and athletes call flow. Sometimes only afterwards we realise that what just happened was peak performance. Moments filled by a sense of Selflessness. Timelessness, Effortlessness and Richness. Like in deep meditative states, ecstatic dancing to your favourite jam, reading a book that really resonates with you or just expressing yourself creatively. However one attains those states, we feel good afterwards, being engaged in our actions and connected to our senses. Just having an experience of flow once in a while can lift ourselves up and help us withstand the chaos we often
face in our lives. An important part of my personal quest is to keep going back deliberately into states of altered consciousness in order to self actualise. To optimise the way I tap into my potential as a human
being. The are several ways that have proven to work for me personally. First there is a regular
meditative practice including transcendental mediation, contemplation and mindfulness. Then there’s the flow of consciousness journaling in the daily pages: I write down whatever gets stuck in my head without judgement for about 20 minutes. This one helps finding out what produces flow experiences, which is often our dharma, our purpose, what our most inner core strives for. And the writing process helps finding out about some content hiding right in front of
you in your daily habits and actions. Another way to reach the mountaintop, and the one that gave me the first glimpse into the beauty of existence instead of nonexistence and in a way gave my spiritual journey a jumpstart, is the use of entheogens in their various forms. Be it in heroic doses and combined with self-isolation in order to get real inner work done, with comparatively low doses to foster relationships and get connected with our surroundings, or in infinitesimal Microdoses for working on habit manifestation, to help boost creative productivity and problem solving. Note that in order to use psychedelics responsibly as a tool for growth one should also implement softer forms of spiritual
practices into their lives to maintain and not be overwhelmed by higher states of consciousness. These are just a few of the many ways that repeatedly help me find meaning in being and the
repertoire of tools keeps expanding as I live and learn. All of these are just building blocks in the art of human optimisation and slowly but surely help us become what we are, higher versions of ourselves that are more capable and somewhat more
complete than what was before. What are your prefered ways of tapping your human potential? Do you regularly try getting in the zone, into altered states of higher consciousness? How do you bring yourself closer to your
higher self?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="flow" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every once in a while we get these glimpses into what scientists and athletes call flow. Sometimes only afterwards we realise that what just happened was peak performance. Moments filled by a sense of Selflessness. Timelessness, Effortlessness and Richness. Like in deep meditative states, ecstatic dancing to your favourite jam, reading a book that really resonates with you or just expressing yourself creatively. However one attains those states, we feel good afterwards, being engaged in our actions and connected to our senses. Just having an experience of flow once in a while can lift ourselves up and help us withstand the chaos we often face in our lives. An important part of my personal quest is to keep going back deliberately into states of altered consciousness in order to self actualise. To optimise the way I tap into my potential as a human being. The are several ways that have proven to work for me personally. First there is a regular meditative practice including transcendental mediation, contemplation and mindfulness. Then there’s the flow of consciousness journaling in the daily pages: I write down whatever gets stuck in my head without judgement for about 20 minutes. This one helps finding out what produces flow experiences, which is often our dharma, our purpose, what our most inner core strives for. And the writing process helps finding out about some content hiding right in front of you in your daily habits and actions. Another way to reach the mountaintop, and the one that gave me the first glimpse into the beauty of existence instead of nonexistence and in a way gave my spiritual journey a jumpstart, is the use of entheogens in their various forms. Be it in heroic doses and combined with self-isolation in order to get real inner work done, with comparatively low doses to foster relationships and get connected with our surroundings, or in infinitesimal Microdoses for working on habit manifestation, to help boost creative productivity and problem solving. Note that in order to use psychedelics responsibly as a tool for growth one should also implement softer forms of spiritual practices into their lives to maintain and not be overwhelmed by higher states of consciousness. These are just a few of the many ways that repeatedly help me find meaning in being and the repertoire of tools keeps expanding as I live and learn. All of these are just building blocks in the art of human optimisation and slowly but surely help us become what we are, higher versions of ourselves that are more capable and somewhat more complete than what was before. What are your prefered ways of tapping your human potential? Do you regularly try getting in the zone, into altered states of higher consciousness? How do you bring yourself closer to your higher self?]]></summary></entry></feed>